<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Scatterbrain Router</string>
    <string name="title_power">Router status</string>
    <string name="missing_permission">Missing permission: %s</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Scatterbrain Router</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">reference implementation version: </string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="powersave_table">Router status:</string>
    <string name="enable_disable">Toggle power state</string>

    <string name="no_apps">No Scatterbrain enabled apps found.</string>

    <string name="title_identity">Identity Management</string>

    <string name="menu_power">Router status</string>
    <string name="menu_about">About</string>

    <string name="bluetooth_disabled_snackbar">Bluetooth is disabled! Scatterbrain cannot run.</string>
    <string name="wifi_disabled_snackbar">Wifi is disabled, Scatterbrain will be abnormally slow.</string>

    <!-- Preference Titles -->
    <string name="power_header">Power Management</string>
    <string name="general_header">General</string>

    <!-- General Preferences -->
    <string name="identity_share_title">Identity share cap</string>
    <string name="message_share_title">Message share cap</string>
    <string name="incognito_title">Incognito mode</string>
    <string name="sizecap_title">Datastore max size (MB)</string>

    <!-- Power Preferences -->
    <string name="power_mode_title">Power saving mode</string>
    <string-array name="power_modes">
        <item>Active</item>
        <item>Opportunistic</item>
        <item>Passive</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="power_modes_vals">
        <item>@string/powersave_active</item>
        <item>@string/powersave_opportunistic</item>
        <item>@string/powersave_passive</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="pref_enabled">power_enabled</string>

    <!-- identity -->
    <string name="create_hint">Display Name</string>
    <string name="create_dialog_title">Generate new identity</string>
    <string name="create_cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="create_create">Generate</string>
    <string name="chip_owned">Owned!</string>
    <string name="permission_subtext">Edit app permissions for this identity</string>
    <string name="service_not_connected">Service not connected…</string>
    <string name="noid">No identities in datastore</string>


    <!-- location -->
    <string name="grant_location_text">Scatterbrain needs location permission in order to scan for bluetooth and wifi when the app is closed.
    this is used to discover other scatterbrain devices to communicate with.</string>
    <string name="grant_wifi_text">Scatterbrain needs your permission to access nearby wifi devices. This will never be used for location</string>
    <string name="strongly_assert">Scatterbrain needs permission to scan for and interact with nearby bluetooth devices.
        Bluetooth will NEVER be used to collect or track location</string>
    <string name="failed_location_text">If location permission is not granted, scatterbrain will only function in passive mode</string>
    <string name="failed_strongly_assert">If bluetooth permission is not granted scatterbrain will not function correctly.</string>

    <string name="disable_doze_text">Scatterbrain needs permission to disable battery optimizations. This allows scatterbrain to forward and receive messages in the background.</string>

    <string name="pref_optout_crashlytics">optOutCrashlytics</string>
    <string name="pref_enable_crashlytics_title">Opt-out of crash reporting spyware</string>
    <string name="pref_enable_crashlyting_desc">Crashlytics helps me debug issues with scatterbrain, but requires sending data to google. A restart is required to disable after enabling.</string>

    <string name="privacy_link">
        Scatterbrain Router is free software! You too can contribute at <a href="https://github.com/Scatterbrain-DTN/">https://github.com/Scatterbrain-DTN/</a>\n\n

        While we try not to collect any data, in the unlikely event that we accidentally do your data is protected by our <a href="https://scatterbrain-dtn.github.io/privacy">Privacy policy</a>\n\n

        THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE AUTHOR ``AS IS\'\' AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES,
        INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A
        PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHOR BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT,
        INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,
        PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION)
        HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT
        (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED
        OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
    </string>

    <string name="title_activity_identity_import">IdentityImportActivity</string>
    <string name="import_identities">Import Identities</string>

    <string name="wifi_description">
        The NEARBY_WIFI_DEVICES permission is required to perform
        wifi direct operations in the background on newer devices
        this is used in tandem with bluetooth to speed to transfers to nearby
        devices that are capable of wifi direct
    </string>
    <string name="advertise_description">
        The BLUETOOTH_ADVERTISE permission is used to broadcast an anonymous id that nearby devices can connect to.
        The id is randomized frequently to prevent tracking.
    </string>
    <string name="bluetooth_connect_description">
        The BLUETOOTH_CONNECT permission is used to connect to Scatterbrain peers in the background using BLE
    </string>
    <string name="bluetooth_scan_description">
        The BLUETOOTH_SCAN permission is required on newer devices to discover Scatterbrain peers in the background via bluetooth
    </string>
    <string name="location_description">
        The ACCESS_FINE_LOCATION permission is required in order to 
        enable background bluetooth connections while the app is closed. This collects location data for the sole purpose
        of bluetooth network. This data is not shared and does not leave your device.
        Android requires this permission to access wifi and bluetooth. This is a requirement set
        by google to preserve privacy when collecting location data from external device IDs

        This location permission does not actually use the GPS location, it only allows Scatterbrain to
        access the bluetooth adapter. The reason your device requires ACCESS_FINE_LOCATION for bluetooth
        is because some apps use 3rd party bluetooth devices to find your devices approximate location by
        looking up their device ids. Scatterbrain does not do this.
    </string>
    <string name="big_description">
        Scatterbrain is a platform for building rich media apps that don\'t need a data plan to work.
        Using bluetooth, wifi, and your own physical social network. Scatterbrain forwards content to all
        your friends even if they are miles away. Scatterbrain powers an entire ecosystem of 3rd party apps on
        your phone, on your desktop, and beyond! Anyone can make an app leveraging the Scatterbrain Router to
        enable offline communication with any device on the Scatterbrain network.
        So, how is this possible if bluetooth and wifi only work over short ranges? Scatterbrain
        swaps messages with other Scatterbrain enabled phones that you pass on the street and allows them to
        carry your messages to their destination as they go about their own day. Messages spread
        like rumors throughout your neighborhood, powered by human connections!


        To get started using Scatterbrain, first you need to grant a few permissions. These are required for the
        Scatterbrain Router app to access your phone\'s bluetooth/wifi hardware. Press "Next" to begin the setup process"
    </string>
    <string name="battery_description">
        To prevent android from pausing Scatterbrain in the background, it is possible to grant an exemption from automatic battery optimization for Scatterbrain router.
        This should prevent android from killing the Scatterbrain service in the background which should improve performance.
        This is optional, as Scatterbrain will try its best to operate without being killed even without this permission.
        Because most background tasks are run on the bluetooth adapter itself you should not see any noticeable drain on battery
        even if you grant this permission.
    </string>

</resources>